<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./TabelToExcelIcon.png" type="Other" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Write To Excel Template</name>
    <shortDescription>Writes an input table into an existing Excel file</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
		<intro>This node writes the input data table into an existing Excel file without changing its formatting.
			<br/>Alternatively a new file will be created based on the template file formats and data.
			The input data will be written to the second row without header by default (can be changed in the Advanced Options)
			Already populated cells in the input file will be overwritten.
			<br/>The node supports three formats chosen by file extension: XLS,XLSX,XLSM
		</intro>
		<option name="Template File Type">
				Select the file type of your template Excel.
				The same file type will be used for the optional output file.
			</option>
		<option name="Template File - Selected File">
			Enter a valid location where the template Excel is availible.
			This file will be used as template - including the formatting and data.
			The required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint).
		</option>
		<option name="Template Sheet Name Selection">Select which sheet in the template file should be used.
			You can select the sheet by name or by the sheet index.
			by default the first sheet will be used.
		</option>
		<option name="Writing Options">Select if the template file should be overwritten orderedlist
			if a new file should be created.
			<i>Note:</i> If "Create new file" is selected - then you have to specify a output file
		</option>		
		<option name="Output File - Selected File">Enter a valid location where the output file should be created.
			This file will be used as template - including the formatting and data.
			The required syntax of a path depends on the chosen file system, such as &quot;C:\path\to\file&quot; (Local
				File System on Windows) or  &quot;/path/to/file&quot; (Local
	            File System on Linux/MacOS and Mountpoint).
		</option>
		<option name="Output File - Overwrite Options">Select if the node should fail - if the new file already exists.
			Or if the existing file should be overwritten.
		</option>
		<option name="Write Options - Write column header">Select if the input table column headers should be written into the first row.
			By default no column header will be written.
		</option>		
		<option name="Write Options - Do not write '=' cells as formulas">Select if string columns containing = should be escaped by '
			so they are not interpreted as formulas.
		</option>	
		<option name="Should all exising formulas be recalculated?">Select if you want to recalculate all existing formulas in your Excel
			file.
		</option>			
		
			
		<option name="Offsets">Select on which row/column the writer should start.
			By default the input table will write from A2 till the last row of the input table.
			If you want to shift this by 2 rows and 1 column (so starting at C4):
				Starting row: 4
				Starting column: 3
			If you want to append the input table to the end of the template file,
			then select the "Write to last physical row" option
		</option>	
		<option name="Template file password">If you template file is secured by a password.
			Then enter your Excel password here.
			The following password options are availible:
				No PWD needed = the file does not have an password and no password should be added to the output
				Open with PWD = file has an password and the password should be the same in the output
				Remove PWD = file has an password, but output should not be secured
				Change PWD = file has an password, but output should have a different password
				Add PWD = file has no password, but output should be secured
		</option>			
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input table">Table that contains columns to write to Excel.
			Most column types are supported. (Strings, Integer, Double, Timestamps, PNG Pictures and file paths.
			If you want to create formulas, then start a String column with '=' followed by the formula. (the formula has to use the english function names) 
		</inPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>